Guide to the Franklin D. Wright Papers, 1790-1897
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Franklin D. Wright papers 1790-1897
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Wright, Franklin D.
2.5 linear feet Extent: approx. 550 Items
Franklin D. Wright was a lawyer from Auburn, New York in the mid-to late 19th century. Collection includes correspondence, legal papers, financial papers, and 4 volumes. The collection ranges in date from 1790-1897.
RL.02066
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Franklin D. Wright Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1955.
Biographical Note
Franklin D. Wright was a laywer in Auburn, New York in the mid-to late 19th century. He practiced in the Law Offices of F. D. and J. A. Wright with his brother, James A. Wright. The work of the firm appears to be related to debts and indentures.
Collection Overview
The collection includes professional correspondence, bills and receipts of clientele, legal papers and indentures, and a woman's diary. Some of the materials appear to pre-date Wright's work.
Subject Headings
Wright, Franklin D.; Lawyers -- New York (State).; Lawyers -- New York (State)--Correspondence; Women -- Personal Narratives
Contents of Collection
- Container List, (4 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1826-1870 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1827-1916
  - Legal Papers, 1790-1848
  - Legal Papers, 1850-1885
  - Bills and Receipts, 1815-1847
  - Bills and Receipts, 1847-1850
  - Articles for Widows and Minor Children, undated
  - Woman's Diary, 1852 (Box 2)
  - Volume of Correspondence (fragile), 1865-1866
  - Volume of Correspondence (fragile), 1857-1858 (Box 3)
  - Volume of Correspondence (fragile), 1867-1870 (Box 4)